Contact

(769)798-8279 (Mobile) tope.daram@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/topedaramola (LinkedIn)

topedaramola.com (Portfolio) github.com/toped (Other)

Top Skills

Adobe ColdFusion Transact-SQL (T-SQL) RabbitMQ

Certifications

Swift Training
Microsoft Certified: Azure

Fundamentals

Information Assurance Certification

Level Up to iOS 8

Introduction to Angular

Honors-Awards

Deans' Scholar

Tope Daramola

Software Engineer at Microsoft

Dallas, Texas, United States

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history. Passionate technical leader that is committed to driving progress by delivering results. Tope leads and serves by example to strengthen relationships, build trust, and encourage collaboration between teams. Armed with his experience and understanding of technology, he not only gets things done, but encourages and leads others to do the same.

Experience

Microsoft
Software Engineer II
November 2021 - Present (3 years 6 months)
Dallas, Texas, United States

Capital One Software Engineer May 2021 - November 2021 (7 months)

AT&T

3 years 11 months

Professional - Software Engineer September 2019 - May 2021 (1 year 9 months) Dallas, Texas

Professional - Applications Developer September 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 1 month) Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Sr. Specialist - Technology Development Program (Software Dev/ Scrum Master)

July 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Gather and analyze product owner requirements to fully understand the goals, scope, and domain of the software tools required of the product owner
- Aid in the agile development process, documentation, and maintenance of inward and outward facing software tools that provide high business unit impact
- Facilitate the sprint planning, daily standup meetings, code reviews, and retrospectives for the development team

Mississippi State University 4 years 3 months

Software Applications Developer July 2014 - July 2017 (3 years 1 month)

Bost Extension Building (190 Bost)

- Design and develop software for various platforms including, but not limited to, iOS applications and web browser applications
- Analyze software needs to design, create, and test software to serve the needs of the MSU Extension service and its clientele
- Collaborate within a software development team to develop applications that solve real world problems

Student Programmer
May 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 3 months)
Bost Extension Building (190 Bost)

- Developed and release iOS applications under Mississippi Extension
 Services. Applications ranged from apps for extension directory listings to apps
 that show an economic snapshot of Mississippi
- Utilized prior programming knowledge to ensure web and mobile apps were production ready
- Employed skills in a wide variety of technologies including HTML, CSS, PHP, C#, and Objective C

Mississippi State University
Webmaster for I.M.A.G.E. Program
August 2010 - August 2012 (2 years 1 month)
Mississippi State University

- Performed website maintenance by updating website modules, and website content
- Increased overall visual appeal and aesthetics of the I.M.A.G.E webpage by adding new media

 Cooperated with campus IT personnel for guidelines and requirements for website maintenance

JCPenney
Sales Associate
May 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 3 months)
Rigland, MS

- Provided excellent customer service to all customers that visited my department
- · Constantly engaged with customers to discover and satisfy their needs
- Adapted to various departments regarding prices and unfamiliar needs of customers in those areas

Mississippi State University Entrepreneurship Center Student Assistant

August 2009 - December 2009 (5 months)

Mississippi State University

- · Provided front desk assistance to visitors
- · Scheduled meetings for supervisor in office
- Assisted with filing papers and other various office tasks

Vector Marketing Sales Representative June 2009 - July 2009 (2 months) Jackson, MS

As a sales representative, I designed schedules for sales and display appointments, performed sales functions for a wide array of products to various customers in the surrounding area, developed and presented sales and marketing presentations to management as required, prepared and performed presentations in accordance with company guidelines.

Education

Mississippi State University

Master's Degree, Computer Science · (2015 - 2017)

Mississippi State University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering (2009 - 2014)

Murrah High School

High School Diploma · (2005 - 2009)